# Kai Geffen

Phone: 413-409-2927

**Location:** Boston, Massachusetts **Email:** GeffenKai@Gmail.com

GitHub: KaiGeffen

#### **Software Engineer**

Versatile and determined software engineer with 5 years of client and industry experience. Enthusiastic learner who consistently explores new technologies and frameworks to continue improving as a developer, collaborator, and engineer. Brings years of experience in managing, facilitating, and communicating with clients and peers in order to achieve excellence in software solutions.

#### **Professional Experience**

### Summer 2020 -Winter 2022

#### Software Engineer

Independent Project - CelestialTCG.com - Boston, MA

- Designed, built, and host a web-app game using Typescript for client-side code, Python for server-side, and Postgres for user database
- Used Websockets for connecting to the server, OAuth for account management, Git for version-control, DigitalOcean for cloud hosting, and Canvas for frontend visuals
- Hired and managed a 4 person team working to develop the art, user-interface, and sound experience for the game

# Winter 2020 - Spring 2021

#### **Software Engineer**

Freelance - Boston, MA

- Collaborated and advised client on successfully designing, executing, and testing a prototype software project
- Developed user experience with Python as well as audio mixing and device configuration
- Created an outline MVP for an audio processing application

## Winter 2018 -Summer 2019

#### Website Redesign Project Manager

Dance New England / Limus Design - dne.org - Boston, MA

- Managed a committee in redesigning a nonprofit organization's website
- Wrote an RFP, reviewed and interviewed candidates for web-designer, content writer, and editor
- Used Wordpress and CPanel to update and host the website

#### **Education**

Summer 2017	Master's of Science in Computer Science (Incomplete) University of Massachusetts Amherst (Privacy and Security focus)
Fall 2016	Bachelor of Science in Computer Science University of Massachusetts Amherst (3.77 Major GPA)
Spring 2012	Associate of Science in Mechanical Engineering Greenfield Community College (3.93 Overall GPA)

#### **Areas of Expertise**

•	Typescript	<ul><li>Python</li></ul>	• Git	<ul> <li>MySQL</li> </ul>
•	OCaml	<ul><li>Ruby</li></ul>	<ul><li>Scala</li></ul>	<ul><li>Java</li></ul>

#### **Other Roles and Achievements**

**Tutored math:** Hundreds of hours of experience working with more than 10 clients over a 10 year period. Many clients returned and demonstrated improved results and understanding.

**Internship at Fiksu:** Used Ruby to create a tool that emulates user interaction with the company's mobile marketing product. Handled the division of a large Ruby Gem into smaller Gems for ease of use throughout the company.

**Internship at Atalasoft:** Extensively tested new features and updates to the company's image processing SDK. Wrote and facilitated the use of a C# program which automatically merged source code comments with the online documentation for the entire SDK.

**Placed on a national math test:** Placed 4<sup>th</sup> in the Northeast on the American Mathematical Association of Two-Year Colleges (AMATYC).

**Contributed to a paper:** Used Scala and propositional logic to fully describe all commands within the functional capacity of Puppet, a configuration manager. Analyzed which orders of execution caused it to fail.

**Served on the Board of Directors:** Served on the Board of a non-profit, consensus based organization which runs an annual 2 week event for over 600 participants. Learned to facilitate, delegate, and communicate effectively with other directors and the community.